# CÉSAR MOLTÓ MORILLA

## VIDEO GAME PROGRAMMER

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a video game programmer specialized in Gameplay Programming who loves creating interactive experiences that users find immersive, intuitive, and challenging.

I am passionate about technology, sports, and travelling. When I am not working or studying, I like to play competitive video games, watch movies, or do outdoor sports and martial arts.

## SKILLS

C / C++ / C# / JAVA / GLSL / BLUEPRINTS (UE4 VISUAL SCRIPTING)

UNREAL ENGINE 4 / UNITY 3D / VISUAL STUDIO / ANDROID STUDIO

GAMEPLAY + AI PROGRAMMING / PHYSICS + GRAPHICS + VR PROGRAMMING

GIT / MERCURIAL / GITHUB / PERFORCE

TEAM WORK / AGILE METHODS / PROJECT MANAGEMENT

## LANGUAGES

**ENGLISH** 

Full Professional Proficiency | CAE (C1)

**GERMAN** 

Elementary | A2 level

**JAPANESE** 

Beginner | Around N5 level

**SPANISH AND CATALAN** 

Mother tongue | Native level

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**EMAIL** 

cmoltomorilla@gmail.com

**WEBSITE** 

https://cesarmolto.github.io

**PHONE NUMBER** 

+34 620 893 530

SKYPE

srmolto

## **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF ALICANTE

SPAIN

Multimedia Engineering Degree

2016 - Present

· Specialization in Creation of Digital Entertainment.

• GPA: 7.73 / 10

#### ATHLONE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

**IRELAND** 

Software Engineering Exchange Year (Erasmus K103)

2018 - 2019

· Specialization in Game Programming.

• GPA: 8.93 / 10

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **HANDY GAMES**

## WÜRZBURG, GERMANY

Game programmer intern

September 2020 - March 2021

- Testing and troubleshooting for bugs and stability as well as ensuring correct documentation.
- Implementation of game controller input and UI with C++ and a custom game engine.
- Collaborate closely with other programmers, designers, testers, and artists to make sure that the game application meets functional and performance requirements.

#### **4FREAKSFICTION**

REMOTE

Game programmer

October 2018 - September 2020

- Volunteer work at this junior enterprise for PC and Mobile game development.
- Coordinated code with other programmers to prototype and implement new gameplay features in Unity 3D; i.e., combat and interaction mechanics, player controls, etc...

## **PROJECTS**

## **DODGEBALL MASTERS**

Gameplay and Engine programmer, Project Manager

2019 - 2020

Supervised and programmed a dodgeball multiplayer game with 8 playable characters and +20 unique skills using C++ and OpenGL. **Source code:** https://github.com/Woko103/Dodgeball Masters

#### **BATTLE TANK**

Programmer and Designer

2019

Developed a head-to-head tank fight game with AI-controlled enemies, pathfinding, and an advanced control system in UE4.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/battle-tank.html

## **BAT HUNTER TANUKI: THE REVENGE**

Programmer and Designer

2018 - 2019

Programmed and designed a Japanese folklore-inspired game in one week for the 2 Buttons Jam 2018.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/bat-hunter-tanuki.html

#### **ROOM MAKER VR**

Programmer, Designer, and Project Manager

2017 - 2018

Led a 4 people team in programming and designing a Virtual Reality scenario editor with Unity 3D and Oculus hardware.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/room-maker.html